Guide to the Stanley M. Issacs Neighborhood Center (New York, NY) Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Executive Director Correspondence
  - General Correspondence, March 1987 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, April 1987 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, May 1987 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, June 1987 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, July 1987 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, August 1987 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, September 1987 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, October 1987 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, November 1987 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, December 1987 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, January 1988 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, February 1988 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, March 1988 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, April 1988 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, May 1988 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, June 1988 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, July 1988 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, August 1988 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, September 1988 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, October 1988 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, November 1988 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, December 1988 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, January 1989 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, February 1989 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, March 1989 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, April 1989 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, May 1989 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, June 1989 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, July 1989 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, August 1989 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, September 1989 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, October 1989 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, November 1989 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, December 1989 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, January 1990 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, February 1990 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, March 1990 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, April 1990 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, May 1990 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, June 1990 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, July 1990 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, August 1990 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, September 1990 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, October 1990 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, November 1990 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, December 1990 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, July 1991 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, August 9-15 1991 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, August 19 1991 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, August 20-31 1991 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, September 1991 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, October 1991 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, November 21 1991 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, December 12 1991 (Box 41, Folder 8)
- Series V: Programs and Services
  - Adult and Family Learning Center, 1987-94 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Adult and Family Learning Center-Publications, 1992-93 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Adult and Senior Services, 1977-93 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Case Log, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Deceased Cases (A-B), 1975-91 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Deceased Cases (C-D), 1975-91 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Deceased Cases (Goebel), 1978-91 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Deceased Cases (Golding), 1975-90 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Deceased Cases (Homlok), 1983-89 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Deceased Cases (G-K), 1975-91 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Deceased Cases (L-O), 1984-91 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Deceased Cases (P-R), 1975-91 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Deceased Cases (Schwartz), 1976-90 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Deceased Cases (S-W), 1983-91 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Reports, 1984-86 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Reports, 1987-90 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Adult and Senior Services-Staff Meetings, 1986-87 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - After School, 1985-91 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Camp Programs, 1978-93 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - East Harlem Tutorial Program, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Elders at Home, 1989-93 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Family Center, 1983-85 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Family Center, 1986-87 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Helping Hand Circle, 1966 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Independent Living Program, 1984-89 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Independent Living Program-Proposals, 1989-90 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Intergenerational Programs, 1970 1987-88 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Meals on Wheels, 1967-74 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Meals on Wheels, 1981-90 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Meals on Wheels-Deceased Cases (F), 1985-91 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Meals on Wheels-Deceased Cases (H-K), 1988-91 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Meals on Wheels-Deceased Cases (Ma), 1987-91 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Meals on Wheels-Deceased Cases (Mc), 1987-91 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Meals on Wheels-Deceased Cases (Mi-O), 1987-91 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Meals on Wheels-Correspondence, 1967-73 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Meals on Wheels-Correspondence, 1981-89 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals, 1974-86 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Neighborhood Prevention Network, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Program Descriptions, 1968-94 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Program Reports, 1982-90 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Retired Senior Volunteer Program, 1975-82 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Senior Resident Advisory Program, 1978-89 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Social Activities for the Frail Elderly, 1982-90 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Social Activities for the Frail Elderly-"El Bohio," 1989-91 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Social Activities for the Frail Elderly-Funding, 1982-88 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Social Activities for the Frail Elderly-Reports, 1982-84 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Social Activities for the Frail Elderly-Reports, 1985-86 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Social Activities for the Frail Elderly-Reports, 1987-88 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Social Activities for the Frail Elderly-Reports, 1989-90 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Support and Training Results in Valuable Employment (STRIVE), 1990-94 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Youth Employment, 1968-86 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Youth Employment, 1987-94 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Youth in Criminal Justice, 1985-88 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Youth Services, 1971-94 (Box 47, Folder 3)
- Series VI: Audio-Visual Material
  - Photographs-Summer Teen Adventure, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Photographs-Knickerbocker Plaza, ca. 1975 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Photographs-Senior Programs, 1970s-80's (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Oversize Rolls:
    - Architectural Drawings-Stanley M. Isaacs Houses, 1959-62 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Architectural Drawings-John Haynes Holmes Towers, 1964-66 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Architectural Drawings-Stanley M. Isaacs Neighborhood Center, nd-1987 (Box 47, Folder 3)
- Name and Subject Index
  - Achelis Foundation – Box 12 Folder 6
  - Adelphi University – Box 32 Folder 2
  - American Express – Box 12 Folder 8
  - Anderson, Warren – Box 33 Folder 3
  - Astor Foundation – Box 13 Folder 2
  - Badillo, Herman – Box 45 Folder 5
  - Bank Street College – Box 38 Folder 2, 5 – Box 39 Folder 4
  - BEA Associates – Box 13 Folder 6
  - Blue Hill Troupe – Box 13 Folder 8
  - The Bodman Foundation – Box 13 Folder 9
  - The Brick Church – Box 13 Folder 11 – Box 45 Folder 5
  - The Brick Presbyterian Church – Box 14 Folder 1
  - Brokaw, Tom – Box 32 Folder 1-2, 5
  - Burden, Carter – Box 45 Folder 5
  - Louis Calder Foundation – Box 14 Folder 4-5
  - Citibank – Box 14 Folder 9
  - City of New York, Board of Education – Box 2 Folder 4-5 – Box 33 Folder 2, 4-5 – Box 38 Folder 7 – Box 39 Folder 1-3 – Box 40 Folder 5
  - City of New York, Community Development Agency – Box 35 Folder 2-3 – Box 37 Folder 3 – Box 38 Folder 1, 3 – Box 39 Folder 3 – Box 40 Folder 3
  - City of New York, Department for the Aging – Box 3 Folder 5-13 – Box 4 Folder 1-2 – Box 32 Folder 4-5, 7 – Box 33 Folder 3, 5-7 – Box 34 Folder 1-2, 4 – Box 35 Folder 2-4 – Box 36 Folder 1, 3-4 – Box 37 Folder 1-5 – Box 38 Folder 1, 3, 5 – Box 39 Folder 1-4 – Box 40 Folder 1
  - City of New York, Department of Cultural Affairs – Box 32 Folder 1 – Box 33 Folder 3, 7
  - City of New York, Human Resources Administration – Box 33 Folder 3, 5, 7 – Box 34 Folder 2 – Box 35 Folder 1-2 – Box 36 Folder 4 – Box 37 Folder 2 – Box 38 Folder 7 – Box 40 Folder 2-3
  - City of New York, Youth Bureau – Box 4 Folder 9-11 – Box 32 Folder 2, 5, 7 – Box 33 Folder 2, 7 – Box 34 Folder 1-3, 5 – Box 36 Folder 2-3, 5 – Box 37 Folder 2, 4 – Box 38 Folder 1
  - Columbia University – Box 33 Folder 7 – Box 34 Folder 1 – Box 37 Folder 4 – Box 39 Folder 2
  - Community Board #8 – Box 34 Folder 3
  - Community Board #11 – Box 37 Folder 5
  - Cornell University Medical College – Box 34 Folder 1 – Box 35 Folder 1-2, 4
  - Cuomo, Mario – Box 32 Folder 6 – Box 37 Folder 2, 5
  - Daly, John – Box 33 Folder 3
  - D'Amato, Alfonse – Box 47 Folder 2
  - Davis, Gloria – Box 38 Folder 3 – Box 40 Folder 5
  - Del Toro, Angelo – Box 37 Folder 2 – Box 38 Folder 1 – Box 39 Folder 2, 4 – Box 41 Folder 6
  - December Foundation – Box 15 Folder 7
  - Dinkins, David – Box 32 Folder 7 – Box 33 Folder 5-6 – Box 35 Folder 4 – Box 36 Folder 1, 5 – Box 38 Folder 1, 2, 6 – Box 39 Folder 6
  - Dryfoos, Robert – Box 33 Folder 2, 4 – Box 35 Folder 3 – Box 36 Folder 5 – Box 37 Folder 1-2 – Box 38 Folder 1, 5 – Box 39 Folder 6-7
  - East Harlem Council for Community Improvement – Box 33 Folder 4-5, 7 – Box 34 Folder 3
  - East Side Council on the Aging – Box 32 Folder 1-2
  - Farley, Hugh T. – Box 32 Folder 2
  - Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies – Box 15 Folder 12
  - Fordham University – Box 32 Folder 2
  - Goddard-Riverside Community Center – Box 35 Folder 4
  - Goodman, Roy N. – Box 33 Folder 3,5 – Box 35 Folder 2-3 – Box 37 Folder 1, 3-4 – Box 39 Folder 1, 2, 6 – Box 40 Folder 3 – Box 44 Folder 9 – Box 45 Folder 5
  - Grand Street Settlement – Box 39 Folder 1
  - Grannis, Alexander "Pete" – Box 5 Folder 5 – Box 6 Folder 6 – Box 33 Folder 2-3 – Box 34 Folder 3 – Box 35 Folder 3 – Box 36 Folder 4 – Box 37 Folder 2 – Box 38 Folder 1, 7 – Box 39 Folder 2 – Box 44 Folder 9
  - Green, Bill – Box 47 Folder 2
  - Grosvenor Neighborhood House – Box 34 Folder 4
  - Heckscher Foundation for Children – Box 16 Folder 12
  - Henry Street Settlement – Box 38 Folder 3
  - Herzfeld Foundation – Box 16 Folder 13
  - Houghton, Amory – Box 32 Folder 7
  - Hudson Guild – Box 34 Folder 4
  - Hunter College – Box 33 Folder 4
  - IBM – Box 17 Folder 1
  - J.M. Kaplan Fund – Box 17 Folder 4
  - Javits, Jacob K. – Box 45 Folder 5
  - Koch, Edward I. – Box 33 Folder 2 – Box 34 Folder 3 – Box 35 Folder 2 – Box 37 Folder 5 – Box 38 Folder 1
  - Lane Bryant Malsin Foundation – Box 17 Folder 14
  - Lehman College – Box 42 Folder 3
  - Lavanburg Corner House – Box 17 Folder 9
  - Edith and Herbert Lehman Foundation – Box 17 Folder 10
  - Lenox Hill Hospital – Box l3 Folder 53 – Box 36 Folder 4
  - Lenox Hill Neighborhood Association – Box 6 Folder 7 – Box 10 Folder 6-8 – Box 36 Folder 4-5 – Box 37 Folder 1-2 – Box 46 Folder 1
  - Marchi, John – Box 33 Folder 3
  - Matz Foundation – Box 18 Folder 1
  - Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center – Box 32 Folder 2
  - Memton Fund – Box 18 Folder 3
  - Mendez, Olga – Box 5 Folder 2
  - Merril Lynch – Box 18 Folder 4
  - Messinger, Ruth – Box 38 Folder 6 – Box 39 Folder 3, 6-7 – Box 40 Folder 2 – Box 41 Folder 6
  - Metropolitan Hospital – Box 33 Folder 4 – Box 34 Folder 3 – Box 35 Folder 2-3 – Box 36 Folder 1 – Box 38 Folder 3 – Box 39 Folder 4
  - Miller, Melvin – Box 36 Folder 3
  - Mobil Foundation – Box 18 Folder 7
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Company – Box 18 Folder 9
  - Henry and Lucy Moses Fund – Box 18 Folder 10
  - Mount Sinai Hospital – Box 35 Folder 4 – Box 36 Folder 5 – Box 39 Folder 2 – Box 41 Folder 6
  - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick – Box 40 Folder 2 – Box 47 Folder 2
  - New York City Housing Authority – Box 6 Folder 5-14 – Box 7 Folder 1-2 – Box 32 Folder 4 – Box 33 Folder 7 – Box 34 Folder 2-3 – Box 35 Folder 2-4 – Box 37 Folder 2 – Box 38 Folder 4 – Box 39 Folder 2, 6-7 – Box 40 Folder 3 – Box 41 Folder 6
  - New York Community Trust – Box 19 Folder 3-4
  - New York Foundation – Box 19 Folder 1-2
  - New York Hospital-Cornell Medical Center – Box 33 Folder 4 – Box 35 Folder 4 – Box 36 Folder 2, 4 – Box 37 Folder 5 – Box 39 Folder 1 – Box 40 Folder 2
  - New York Times Company Foundation – Box 19 Folder 6
  - New York University – Box 35 Folder 4 – Box 39 Folder 1
  - Norman Foundation – Box 20 Folder 2
  - Riverdale Neighborhood House – Box 34 Folder 4
  - Helena Rubenstein Foundation – Box 21 Folder 1
  - Rubin Foundation – Box 21 Folder 2
  - School of Visual Arts – Box 35 Folder 4 – Box 37 Folder 4
  - Schumer, Charles – Box 32 Folder 7
  - Seigel, Mark – Box 34 Folder 3 – Box 37 Folder 2 – Box 39 Folder 2
  - State of New York, Department of Social Services – Box 4 Folder 13 – Box 5 Folder 1 – Box 34 Folder 5 – Box 35 Folder 1-2 – Box 39 Folder 1, 6 – Box 41 Folder 6
  - State of New York, Department of Youth Services – Box 39 Folder 1-3
  - Surdna Foundation – Box 21 Folder 10
  - Sutton, Percy – Box 45 Folder 5
  - Taconic Foundation – Box 21 Folder 11
  - Temple Shaaray Tefila – Box 22 Folder 1
  - Oakleigh L. Thorne Foundation – Box 22 Folder 2
  - Union Settlement Association – Box 32 Folder 2 – Box 35 Folder 2
  - United Neighborhood Houses – Box 7 Folder 16-17 – Box 22 Folder 5 – Box 23 Folder 8 – Box 39 Folder 2 – Box 40 Folder 5
  - United Way of New York – Box 22 Folder 6 – Box 32 Folder 2
  - Vinmont Foundation – Box 22 Folder 9
  - Weprin, Saul – Box 34 Folder 4
  - Yorkville Civic Council – Box l7 Folder 20 – Box 33 Folder 7
  - Yorkville Emergency Alliance – Box 22 Folder 13